Chiang 姜成翰

🗷 dcml0714@gmail.com | 🛠 d223302.github.io | 🖸 d223302 | 💆 @dcml0714 | 🕿 Cheng-Han, Chiang

About me_

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at National Taiwan University in Taipei, Taiwan. I am a member of the Speech Processing and Machine Learning (SPML) Lab, and I am very lucky to be advised by Prof. Hung-yi Lee. My main research interests broadly cover different aspects of natural language processing (NLP), mainly involving self-supervised learning, interpretability and analysis of NLP Models, adversarial attacks, and human evaluation.

Education

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Taipei. Taiwan

PH.D. STUDENT IN COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Feb 2022 - Present

- · Advisor: Hung-yi Lee
- · Direct pursuit of the Ph.D. degree
- M.S student in Graduate Institute of Communication Engineering (GICE) at National Taiwan University from Sep. 2020 to Jan. 2022

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Taipei, Taiwan

Sept 2016 - June 2020

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Research Experience _____

Supervisor: Dr. Hung-yi Lee

Taipei, Taiwan

August. 2020 - Present

- NTU Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab.
- Large language models and self-supervised learning [2, 4, 7, 6, 5] • Automatic evaluations and human evaluations in NLP [2, 4, 1, 9]
- Adversarial attacks in NLP [3, 10]

Publications

In Proceedings

Why We Should Report the Details in Subjective Evaluation of TTS More Rigorously Cheng-Han Chiang, Wei-Ping Huang, Hung-yi Lee Proc. Interspeech 2023, 2023, Dublin, Ireland

[2] A Closer Look into Automatic Evaluation Using Large Language Models Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2023, 2023, Singapore

Are Synonym Substitution Attacks Really Synonym Substitution Attacks? Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2023, 2023, Toronto, Canada

Can Large Language Models Be an Alternative to Human Evaluation? Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 61th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linquistics (Volume 1: Long Papers), 2023, Toronto, Canada

Recent Advances in Pre-trained Language Models: Why Do They Work and How Do They Work

Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2nd Conference of the Asia-Pacific Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 12th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing: Tutorial Abstracts, 2022, Taipei

On the transferability of pre-trained language models: A study from artificial datasets Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

Pretrained Language Model Embryology: The Birth of ALBERT

Cheng-Han Chiang, Sung-Feng Huang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020, Online

Workshop Papers

Revealing the Blind Spot of Sentence Encoder Evaluation by HEROS

Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, James Glass, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP, 2023, Toronto, Canada

[9] Re-Examining Human Annotations for Interpretable NLP

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Explainable Agency in Artificial Intelligence Workshop of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

Preprints

[10] Understanding, Detecting, and Separating Out-of-Distribution Samples and Adversarial Samples in Text Classification **Cheng-Han Chiang**, Hung-yi Lee

arXiv preprint arXiv:2204.04458 (2022)2022

Professional Talks

CONFERENCE TUTORIALS

ICASSP 2023 Rhodes Island, Greece

PARAMETER-EFFICIENT LEARNING FOR SPEECH AND LANGUAGE PROCESSING: ADAPTERS, PROMPTS, AND REPROGRAMMING

2023

• Tutorial speaker for parameter-efficient learning in NLP

AACL-IJCNLP 2022 Virtua

RECENT ADVANCES IN PRE-TRAINED LANGUAGE MODELS: WHY DO THEY WORK AND HOW DO THEY WORK

• Main organizer of the tutorial

- Tutorial website: https://d223302.github.io/AACL2022-Pretrain-Language-Model-Tutorial/
- Tutorial recordings: https://youtu.be/thr4-hgLhi8

Honors & Awards

2023 Google PhD Fellowship, Google Global

2022 **Elite Doctoral Scholarship**, National Taiwan University *Taipei, Taiwan*

2021 Advanced Speech Technologies Scholarship, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Professional Activities

PROGRAM COMMITTEE 2021-Present

Reviewer at ICML (2023), ACL (2022-2023), EACL (2023), AAAI (2023), NeurIPS (2022-2023), ICLR (2022-2024), EMNLP (2021-2023) and ARR

JOURNAL REVIEWER 2023-Present

• Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing: 2023

Teaching Assistants _____

Machine Learning: 2020 Spring, 2021 Spring, 2022 Spring, 2023 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

Feb. - Jun. 2020 - 2023

TEACHING ASSISTANT

• Gave a 2-hour lecture on diverse topics of large language models.

- Gave a 2-hour lecture on the recent advances in pre-trained language models. Video is available: https://youtu.be/NzElV8jTNmw
- Gave a 3-hour lecture on the adversarial attacks in NLP. Videos are available: https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg and https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg
- Built, designed, and maintained the course website: https://speech.ee.ntu.edu.tw/~hylee/ml/2021-spring.php
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Gave a 2-hour lecture on graph neural network. Video is available: } \textbf{https://youtu.be/M9ht8vsVEw8}$
- Designed a homework on meta-learning

Deep Learning for Human Language Processing 2020 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020

• In charge of homework on voice conversion

Work Experience _____

National Taiwan University Speech Lab.

Taipei, Taiwan

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR AND NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• Managed a Slurm-based system with 20 GPUs